<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
    <EnglishText>
        <Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_PORCELAIN_TOWER_NAME">
            <Text>Porcelain Tower</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_PORCELAIN_TOWER_DESCRIPTION">
            <Text>Grants three copies of the [ICON_RESOURCE_PORCELAIN] Porcelain Luxury Resource which provide +6 Amenities each. Must be built on a flat Grassland, Plains or Tundra tile.</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_PORCELAIN_TOWER_QUOTE">
            <Text>"In the middle of the Plain stands a high Steeple or Tower made of Porcelane, which far exceed all other Workmanship of the Chinese in cost and skill; by which the Chinese have declared to the World the rare Ingenuity of their Artists in former Ages." - Johannes Nieuhof</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_WONDERS_PAGE_BUILDING_PORCELAIN_TOWER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
            <Text>Constructed by the Ming Dynasty in the 15th century, the Porcelain Tower of Nanjing was one of the most extraordinary architectural achievements of Chinese history. The tower was some 30 meters (97 feet) in diameter, with a height of 79 meters (260 feet).</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_WONDERS_PAGE_BUILDING_PORCELAIN_TOWER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
            <Text>The exterior of the building was built of white porcelain bricks that shone like mirrors in the sunlight. At night the tower was hung from top to bottom with over 100 lamps. The tower stood in the center of Nanjing until 1854 when it was destroyed during the Taiping Rebellion.</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_WONDERS_PAGE_BUILDING_PORCELAIN_TOWER_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
            <Text></Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="LOC_RESOURCE_PORCELAIN_NAME">
            <Text>Porcelain</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_RESOURCES_PAGE_RESOURCE_PORCELAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
            <Text>Porcelain is a ceramic material made by heating materials, generally including kaolin, in a kiln to temperatures between 1,200 and 1,400 °C (2,200 and 2,600 °F). The toughness, strength, and translucence of porcelain, relative to other types of pottery, arises mainly from vitrification and the formation of the mineral mullite within the body at these high temperatures. Though definitions vary, porcelain can be divided into three main categories: hard-paste, soft-paste and bone china. The category that an object belongs to depends on the composition of the paste used to make the body of the porcelain object and the firing conditions.</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_RESOURCES_PAGE_RESOURCE_PORCELAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_2">
            <Text>Porcelain slowly evolved in China and was finally achieved (depending on the definition used) at some point about 2,000 to 1,200 years ago, then slowly spread to other East Asian countries, and finally Europe and the rest of the world. Its manufacturing process is more demanding than that for earthenware and stoneware, the two other main types of pottery, and it has usually been regarded as the most prestigious type of pottery for its delicacy, strength, and its white colour. It combines well with both glazes and paint, and can be modelled very well, allowing a huge range of decorative treatments in tablewares, vessels and figurines. It also has many uses in technology and industry.</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_RESOURCES_PAGE_RESOURCE_PORCELAIN_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_3">
            <Text>The European name, porcelain in English, comes from the old Italian porcellana (cowrie shell) because of its resemblance to the surface of the shell. Porcelain is also referred to as china or fine china in some English-speaking countries, as it was first seen in imports from China. Properties associated with porcelain include low permeability and elasticity; considerable strength, hardness, toughness, whiteness, translucency and resonance; and a high resistance to chemical attack and thermal shock.</Text>
        </Row>
    </EnglishText>
</GameData>