<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 2 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by Ed Beach (Firaxis Games) -->
<GameData>
	<LocalizedText>
		<!--MOD-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_MOD_JFD_RUSSIA_ELISABETH_DESCRIPTION" Language="en_US">
			<Text>------------------------------------[NEWLINE]LEADER -- ELISABETH[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]TRAIT - COURT MASQUERADES[NEWLINE]Receives an [ICON_ENVOY] Envoy when expending a Great Artist, Musician, or Writer. Gain the Arts Institute unique building after researching the Humanism civic.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]BUILDING - ARTS INSTITUTE[NEWLINE]Russian unique building when Elisabeth is their leader. Has 2 slots for any type of Great Work and yields +1 [ICON_GREATARTIST] Great Artist, +1 [ICON_GREATMUSICIAN] Great Musician, and +1 [ICON_GREATWRITER] Great Writer Point per turn. Yields +1 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]AGENDA - COURT SPLENDOUR[NEWLINE]Likes to patronage Cultural Great People, and is impressed by civilizations that are high in [ICON_CULTURE] Culture. Is jealous of civilizations that have Luxury Resources that she doesn't.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--CIVILIZATION-->
		<!--Trait-->
		<Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_CIVILIZATION_MOTHER_RUSSIA_DESCRIPTION" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Extra territory upon founding and conquering cities. +1 [ICON_Faith] Faith and +1 [ICON_Production] Production from Tundra.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_GRAND_EMBASSY_DESCRIPTION" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Receives [ICON_Science] Science or [ICON_Culture] Culture from [ICON_TradeRoute] Trade Routes to civilizations that are more advanced than Russia (+1 per 3 technologies or civics ahead). Gain the Preobrazhensky Regiment unique unit when they research the Military Science technology.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<!--LEADER-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_NAME" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Elisabeth</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Agenda-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_AGENDA_JFD_COURT_SPLENDOUR_NAME" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Court Splendour</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_AGENDA_JFD_COURT_SPLENDOUR_DESCRIPTION" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Likes to patronage Cultural Great People, and is impressed by civilizations that are high in [ICON_CULTURE] Culture. Is jealous of civilizations that have Luxury Resources that she doesn't.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_REASON_DESIRED_LUXURY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>(You have luxuries that she doesn't.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MODIFIER_AGENDA_JFD_COURT_SPLENDOUR_DESIRED_LUXURY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Elisabeth is jealous of your luxury resources</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_REASON_LEADS_PATRONAGE" Language="en_US">
			<Text>(You are competing for Great People.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MODIFIER_AGENDA_JFD_COURT_SPLENDOUR_LEADS_PATRONAGE" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Elisabeth envies your Great People</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DOM-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_LOADING_INFO_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Fine dresses, finer guests, the Russian imperial court begs your presence, beautiful Empress Elisabeth. Invite the splendours of the enlightenment to Russia. Don her in culture and finery, and make your court the envy of monarchs the world over.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Traits-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_JFD_COURT_MASQUERADES_NAME" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Court Masquerades</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_JFD_COURT_MASQUERADES_DESCRIPTION" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Receives an [ICON_ENVOY] Envoy when expending a Great Artist, Musician, or Writer. Gain the Arts Institute unique building after researching the Humanism civic.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_TRAIT_LEADER_JFD_COURT_MASQUERADES_NOTIFICATION" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Elisabeth holds a new Court Masquerade, enciting dignitaries to the Court. Receive +{1_Num} [COLOR_GREEN][ICON_ENVOY] Envoy[ENDCOLOR].</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Civilopedia-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_TITLE" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Elisabeth</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_SUBTITLE" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Empress of Russia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_QUOTE" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Power without a nation's confidence is nothing.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Daughter of Peter I and Catherine I, grand princess and crown princess from 1709 to 1741, Elizabeth (Elizaveta Petrovna) was the second of ten offspring to reach maturity. She was born in the Moscow suburb of Kolomenskoye on December 29, 1709, the same day a Moscow parade celebrated the Poltava victory. Elizabeth grew up carefree with her sister Anna (1708–1728). Doted on by both parents, the girls received training in European languages, social skills, and Russian traditions of singing, religious instruction, and dancing. Anna married Duke Karl Friedrich of Holstein-Gottorp in 1727 and died in Holstein giving birth to Karl Peter Ulrich (the future Peter III). Elizabeth never married officially or traveled abroad, her illegitimate birth obstructing royal matches. Because she wrote little and left no diary, her inner thoughts are not well-known.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Hints of a political role came after her mother's short reign when Elizabeth was named to the joint regency for young Peter II, whose favor she briefly enjoyed. But when he died childless in 1730 she was overlooked in the surprise selection of Anna Ivanovna. Under Anna she was kept under surveillance, her yearly allowance cut to 30,000 rubles, and only Biron's influence prevented commitment to a convent. At Aleksandrovka near Moscow she indulged in amorous relationships with Alexander Buturlin, Alexei Shubin, and the Ukrainian chorister Alexei Razumovsky. During Elizabeth's reign male favoritism flourished; some of her preferred men assumed broad cultural and artistic functions—for instance, Ivan Shuvalov (1717–1797), a well-read Francophile who cofounded Moscow University and the Imperial Russian Academy of Fine Arts in the 1750s.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Anna Ivanovna was succeeded in October 1740 by infant Ivan VI of the Brunswick branch of Romanovs who reigned under several fragile regencies, the last headed by his mother, Anna Leopoldovna (1718–1746). This Anna represented the Miloslavsky/Brunswick branch, whereas Elizabeth personified the Naryshkin/Petrine branch. Elizabeth naturally worried the inept regency regime, which she led her partisans in the guards to overthrow on December 5–6, 1741, with aid from the French and Swedish ambassadors (Sweden had declared war on Russia in July 1741 ostensibly in support of Elizabeth). The bloodless coup was deftly accomplished, the regent and her family arrested and banished, and Elizabeth's claims explicated on the basis of legitimacy and blood kinship. Though Elizabeth's accession unleashed public condemnation of both Annas as agents of foreign domination, it also reaffirmed the primacy of Petrine traditions and conquests, promising to restore Petrine glory and to counter Swedish invasion, which brought Russian gains in Finland by the Peace of Åbo in August 1743.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Elizabeth was crowned in Moscow in spring 1742 amid huge celebrations spanning several months; she demonstratively crowned herself. With Petrine, classical feminine, and "restorationist" rhetoric, Elizabeth's regime resembled Anna Ivanovna's in that it pursued an active foreign policy, witnessed complicated court rivalries and further attempts to resolve the succession issue, and made the imperial court a center of European cultural activities. In 1742 the empress, lacking offspring, brought her nephew from Holstein to be converted to Orthodoxy, renamed, and designated crown prince Peter Fyodorovich. In 1744 she found him a German bride, Sophia of Anhalt-Zerbst, the future Catherine II. The teenage consorts married in August 1745, and hopes for a male heir came true only in 1754. Elizabeth took charge of Grand Prince Pavel Petrovich. Nevertheless, the "Young Court" rivaled Elizabeth's in competition over dynastic and succession concerns.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]	While retaining ultimate authority, Elizabeth restored the primacy of the Senate in policymaking, exercised a consultative style of administration, and assembled a government comprising veteran statesmen, such as cosmopolitan Chancellor Alexei Bestuzhev-Ryumin and newly elevated aristocrats like the brothers Petr and Alexander Shuvalov (and their younger cousin Ivan Shuvalov), Mikhail and Roman Vorontsov, Alexei and Kirill Razumovsky, and court surgeon Armand Lestocq. Her reign generally avoided political repression, but she took revenge on the Lopukhin family, descendents of Peter I's first wife, by having them tortured and exiled in 1743 for loose talk about the Brunswick family and its superior rights. Later she abolished the death penalty in practice. Lestocq and Bestuzhev-Ryumin, who was succeeded as chancellor by Mikhail Vorontsov, fell into disgrace for alleged intrigues, although Catherine II later pardoned both.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In cultural policy Elizabeth patronized many, including Mikhail Lomonosov, Alexander Sumarokov, Vasily Tredyakovsky, and the Volkov brothers, all active in literature and the arts. Foreign architects, composers, and literary figures such as Bartolomeo Rastrelli, Francesco Araja, and Jakob von Stählin also enjoyed Elizabeth's support. Her love of pageantry resulted in Petersburg's first professional public theater in 1756. Indeed, the empress set a personal example by frequently attending the theater, and her court became famous for elaborate festivities amid luxurious settings, such as Rastrelli's new Winter Palace and the Catherine Palace at Tsarskoye Selo. Elizabeth loved fancy dress and followed European fashion, although she was criticized by Grand Princess Catherine for quixotic transvestite balls and crudely dictating other ladies'style and attire. Other covert critics such as Prince Mikhail Shcherbatov accused Elizabeth of accelerating the "corruption of manners" by pandering to a culture of corrupt excess, an inevitable accusation from disgruntled aristocrats amid the costly ongoing Europeanization of a cosmopolitan high society. The Shuvalov brothers introduced significant innovations in financial policy that fueled economic and fiscal growth and reinstituted recodification of law.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Elizabeth followed Petrine precedent in foreign policy, a field she took special interest in, although critics alleged her geographical ignorance and laziness. Without firing a shot, Russia helped conclude the war of the Austrian succession (1740–1748), but during this conflict Elizabeth and Chancellor Bestuzhev-Ryumin became convinced that Prussian aggression threatened Russia's security. Hence alliance with Austria became the fulcrum of Elizabethan foreign policy, inevitably entangling Russia in the reversal of alliances in 1756 that exploded in the worldwide Seven Years' War (1756–1763). This complex conflict pitted Russia, Austria, and France against Prussia and Britain, but Russia did not fight longtime trading partner Britain. Russia held its own against Prussia, conquered East Prussia, and even briefly occupied Berlin in 1760. The war was directed by a new institution, the Conference at the Imperial Court, for Elizabeth's declining health limited her personal attention to state affairs. The war dragged on too long, and the belligerents began looking for a way out when Elizabeth's sudden death on Christmas Day (December 25, 1761) brought her nephew Peter III to power. He was determined to break ranks and to ally with Prussia, despite Elizabeth's antagonism to King Frederick II. So just as Elizabeth's reign started with a perversely declared war, so it ended abruptly with Russia's early withdrawal from a European-wide conflict and Peter III's declaration of war on longtime ally Denmark. Elizabeth personified Russia's post-Petrine eminence and further emergence as a European power with aspirations for cultural achievement.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_CHAPTER_CAPSULE_BODY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Elizabeth's Russia is the spreading amoeba you don’t want next door. She is great at absorbing all the land, great people, and civics around her!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_LEADERS_PAGE_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_CHAPTER_DETAILED_BODY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Russia's bonuses are ideal for taking over large swaths of territory on the ground. First because each city starts large, and second because Lavras gain extra tiles for their city when a Great Person is expended. Russia’s cities will quickly gain lots of tiles. Couple that with Elizabeth's ability to gain bonus Culture and Envoys from expending Cultural Great People, and you have a very powerful empire that can win any type of victory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Diplomacy-->
		<!--FIRST MEET-->
		<!--First AI line-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Charmed to meet you. I am Elisabeth of Russia. Now, if you don't mind, I am late for a masquerade ball, so why don't we hurry this along.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI invitation to visit nearby City-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_VISIT_RECIPIENT_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>I am hosting a masquerade ball in one of my nearby palaces. Won't you join me? You'll have to change into something finer, of course.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI accepts Human invitation-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NEAR_INITIATOR_POSITIVE_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Yes, very well.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI invitation to exchange Capital Information-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_FIRST_MEET_NO_MANS_INFO_EXCHANGE_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Could I get to know a bit more about your Capital? I want to know what court life is like in the underprivileged nations of the world.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--GREETINGS-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_GREETING_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Welcome.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DELEGATION-->
		<!--AI Accepts-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Your delegation dresses in a truly remarkable style. I gladly welcome them at my court anytime.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Rejects-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DELEGATION_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>I have turned away your delegation, on account of that fact that they were improperly dressed. You should know better than to send your stableboy to greet the sovereign of Russian.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Requests -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DELEGATION_FROM_AI_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>I have sent a Russian delegation to your Capital, inviting you to my next masquerade ball. Come dressed in your finest or don't come at all.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--OPEN BORDERS-->
		<!--AI accepts from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Agreeable.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI rejects from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Well, I don't want just anyone coming in. So it has to be no.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI requests from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_OPEN_BORDERS_FROM_AI_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Some of my merchants have had some difficulty navigating around your borders. So you'll agree to open your borders to me and let them through. You wouldn't disappoint me, would you?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DECLARE FRIENDSHIP-->
		<!--AI accepts from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Why, of course. I graciously accept your hand in friendship.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Rejects from human -->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Friends? With you? Hah.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Requests friendship from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>I would very much like it if we were to become good friends. What do you think?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Human accepts AI requests, AI responds-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Well, of course. Who wouldn't want to be my friend?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Human rejects AI requests, AI responds-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>You're joking, right?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--ALLIANCE-->
		<!--AI Requests an alliance from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_ALLIANCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>I would like to spend more time at court and less time with my war ministers, so I'm relying on you to help defend Russia's interests. What do you say about an alliance?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--KUDOS & WARNINGS-->
		<!--AI Kudos-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_KUDO_EXIT_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Handsome, you're welcome back anytime.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Warnings-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_EXIT_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>I think your luxuries are wasted on you, if I'm being candid.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI warns player for border troops-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_WARNING_TOO_MANY_TROOPS_NEAR_ME_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Some of my courtiers have seen fit to interrupt my fun and alert me to your troops gathering at my borders. This upsets me immeasurably and I demand that you move them at once.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--TRADE-->
		<!--AI Accepts Deal-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>{LOC_DIPLO_ACCEPT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Rejects Deal-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_MAKE_DEAL_FROM_AI_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>{LOC_DIPLO_REJECT_DECLARE_FRIEND_FROM_AI_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DENOUNCE-->
		<!--From Human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Don't expect an invite to my next masquerade ball then.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--From AI-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>You have displeased a great many people. (Denounces You)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Rationale-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_REASON_FROM_AI_LEADER_ANY_REASON_JFD_COURT_SPLENDOUR_DESIRED_LUXURY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>(You have a luxury resource that she desires.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DENOUNCE_REASON_FROM_AI_LEADER_ANY_REASON_JFD_COURT_SPLENDOUR_LEADS_GREAT_PEOPLE" Language="en_US">
			<Text>(You are competing for Great People.)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DECLARE WAR-->
		<!--Human Declares War-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Please. I've fought foes worse than you from the comfort of my bed chambers.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Declares War-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DECLARE_WAR_FROM_AI_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Your policies are a threat to Russian interests. Prepare to mobilise your forces. We go to war.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--MAKE PEACE-->
		<!--AI accepts from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_ACCEPT_DEAL_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>A splended idea.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI refuses human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_AI_REFUSE_DEAL_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>No, no I don't think so.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI requests from human-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_MAKE_PEACE_FROM_AI_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>It is time to cease this dull war and return to peace.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DEFEAT-->
		<!--AI is Defeated-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>The Imperial Court shall never be the same without me... I dare say no court shall ever be as splendid again.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Human is Defeated (will see this in hotseat)-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_HUMAN_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY" Language="en_US">
			<Text>[LOC_DIPLO_DEFEAT_FROM_AI_LEADER_JFD_ELISABETH_ANY]</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--ARTS INSTITUTE-->
		<Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_JFD_ART_INSTITUTE_NAME" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Arts Institute</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_BUILDING_JFD_ART_INSTITUTE_DESCRIPTION" Language="en_US">
			<Text>Russian unique building when Elisabeth is their leader. Has 2 slots for any type of Great Work and yields +1 [ICON_GREATARTIST] Great Artist, +1 [ICON_GREATMUSICIAN] Great Musician, and +1 [ICON_GREATWRITER] Great Writer Point per turn. Yields +1 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="LOC_PEDIA_BUILDINGS_PAGE_BUILDING_JFD_ART_INSTITUTE_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1" Language="en_US">
			<Text>The Russian Academy of Arts in Saint Petersburg, informally known as the Saint Petersburg Academy of Arts, was founded in 1757 by Ivan Shuvalov under the name Academy of the Three Noblest Arts, under the patronage of Elisabeth Petrovna. Catherine the Great renamed it the Imperial Academy of Arts and commissioned a new building, completed 25 years later in 1789 by the Neva River. The academy promoted the neoclassical style and technique, and sent its promising students to European capitals for further study. Training at the academy was virtually required for artists to make successful careers.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--MOD SUPPORT-->
	</LocalizedText>
</GameData>
